# Tristan McIntosh, B.Sc. (Hons)

4272 Wakefield Crescent, Mississauga, ON L5C 4M4

Phone: 647-242-8677

tristan.mcintosh1@gmail.com

# Career Summary

Experienced program manager with specialty in air quality, hazardous building materials, and health promotion. Managed multiple air quality projects at the municipal, provincial and national level. Developed policies and best practice standards for various organizations, managed multiple projects simultaneously and provided submissions on government consultations and call for proposals. Excellent technical knowledge of radon, asbestos, mould, air quality and other environmental issues.

# Professional Experience

## The Lung Association - Ontario

Provincial Air Quality Coordinator

October 2017 - Present February 2016 - May 2017

- Developed, implemented, promoted and evaluated air quality awareness and education campaigns
- Created/updated air quality education materials and position statements
- Managed multiple projects simultaneously and developed budgets for departments
- Sourced and secured external funding for air quality promotion initiatives
- Provided Lung Association representation on various groups, committees, health care agencies and other affiliated organizations
- Represented Lung Association on climate change initiatives, including the Clean Economy Alliance as well as the Atmospheric Fund (TAF) communication strategy grant
- Played a leadership role with respect to the national Take Action on Radon (TAOR) project
- Under the Smoke-Free Environment Program Coordinator role, worked to increase the number of smoke free homes/apartments, cars, public spaces, etc. in Ontario
- Organized and coordinated Motivational Interviewing (MI) training workshops in partnership with the Centre for Addiction and Mental Health (CAMH)

#### **OHE Consultants**

Senior Project Specialist

May 2017 - October 2017

- Implemented asbestos and hazardous building materials management services for clients
- Drafted and submitted compliance reports to clients, including designated substances surveys, inspection reports, etc.
- Applied ministry regulations in various projects such as air quality and hazardous building materials
- Assisted with preparing bid documents including specifications, scope of work, and drawings
- Performed air monitoring for asbestos and analysis by phase contrast microscopy (PCM)

## **ECOH Management Inc.**

Environmental Scientist

August 2013 - November 2015

- Interpreted and implemented government guidelines, regulations and legislation in multiple projects
- Prepared and submitted reports and proposals for various clients and stakeholders
- Built and maintained clients relationships at the residential and commercial level
- Completed inspections and site surveys of projects (asbestos, lead, mould, and designated substances) to monitor compliance with specifications, industry standards and applicable regulations
- Completed Asbestos Awareness Training and Indoor Air Quality and Mould Training

## Sierra Flower Trading Ltd.

Quality Control Assistant Manager

November 2010 - August 2013

- Developed quality control reports for sales associates and clients
- Supervised staff, provided coaching in process, quality control and equipment
- Performed quality inspections in order to ensure product meets and surpassed industry standards

## City of Mississauga

Intern, Parks Planning

September 2010 - March 2011

- Focused the City's attention on increasing natural areas by assisting with the drafting of the Scope for the Natural Heritage Systems Strategy
- Helped to develop a sustainable and environmentally responsible master plan for the parkland and natural areas along the Credit River in Mississauga
  - o Facilitated feedback from residents and others by assisting with the development of a public engagement plan and supporting Community and Stakeholder meeting logistics
- Developed an extensive background review for Streetsville Memorial Park, Erindale Park, Riverwood and the Former Pinchin and Harris properties

#### University of Toronto Mississauga (UTM) Green Team

Alternative Transportation Coordinator

September 2009 - March 2010

- Promoted and coordinated alternative transportation events throughout the University
- Conducted surveys and organized student information on behalf of Smart Commute (City of Mississauga) as a part of the Stepping it Up initiative

#### Education

# University of Toronto Mississauga (UTM)

Honours B.Sc. (2011), Double Major in Environmental Management and Psychology

- Environmental Sustainability Practicum
  - Researched best-in-class bicycling programs and presented the findings to stakeholders, including the City of Mississauga, the Riverwood Conservancy, and Smart Commute
  - Conducted and facilitated focus groups at the University of Toronto Mississauga and acted as the lead facilitator
  - Developed educational material regarding alternative and sustainable methods of transportation and delivered it to University stakeholders
- Authored an environmental article for the University of Toronto Mississauga Newspaper (The Medium) regarding "Green Transportation"

#### **Activities and Interests**

- Successfully completed the Resource Environmental Associates Ltd. Cannabis Legalization: Implications for Occupational Health and Safety Course (2018)
- Social Committee member at the Lung Association Ontario (2018)
- Successfully completed Ministry of Labour approved Working at Heights Training (2017)
- Social Committee member at ECOH Management Inc. (2014-2015)
- Active member of LA Fitness Club (2013-Present)
- Member at the University of Toronto Mississauga Recreational and Wellness Centre (2006 2013)
- University of Toronto Mississauga Intramural Basketball League (2007 2010)
- Volunteered at the Square One Youth Centre (SOYC)